Well, that's a fantastic result to have now arrived towards the end of week one and having completed
정말 멋진 결과예요 첫째 주가 끝나가는데 흥미진진한 프로젝트를
a substantial and exciting project.
완성했잖아요
Now, of course, there are some challenges for you.
물론 어려운 점도 있죠
This is where it gets interesting.
여기서부터가 재미있어요
First of all, I have some challenges, which is things that you can do to make this project better,
우선, 어려운 점이 몇 가지 있습니다 이 프로젝트를 더 좋게 만들 수 있는 방법입니다
similar to things I just mentioned a moment ago.
조금 전에 말씀드린 것과 비슷하죠
And then after that there is an exercise, a proper work through homework assignment for you where you
그 후에는 숙제를 내주는 실습이 있습니다 처음부터 다
have to build something from scratch.
만들어야 하죠
And of course, I do provide a solution when you're ready for it, but I don't think you'll need it
물론 준비되시면 해결책을 제공하겠지만 필요 없을 것 같네요
because I think you got this.
이게 있으니까요
Let's start with the challenges.
과제부터 시작하죠
So first of all, uh, in the when we built the the brochure maker that we've already got, there are,
먼저, 이미 있는 브로슈어 제작기를 만들 때 LMS에 두 번
of course, the two calls to the LMS.
전화를 걸었어요
The first call I described as one shot prompting because we give an example of some JSON of how it should
첫 번째 호출은 원샷 프롬프트라고 설명했어요 어떻게 응답해야 하는지에 대한 JSON 예제를 보여드렸거든요
And now I mentioned before that there's also this expression multi-shot prompting, which is when you
아까도 언급했지만 다중 샷 프롬프트라는 표현이 있습니다 여러 개의
provide multiple examples.
예제를 제공하는 것을 말하죠
And so that's what I would like you to do, extend this to have multi shot prompting and really to make
그게 제가 여러분께 원하는 겁니다 이걸 확장해 멀티 샷 프롬핑으로 진정한 멀티 샷 프롬핑이
it true multi-shot prompting.
되게 하는 거죠
The way you would do is you'd say something like, so if I show you these links, you might reply like
이렇게 하는 거죠 이 링크들을 보여드리면 이렇게 답장하고 JSON을
this and give it some JSON, clearly indicating where you've only selected the relevant links and how
주는 거예요 어디서 관련 링크만 선택했는지 경로를 어떻게 정정했는지를
you fully qualified the path.
분명히 알려주죠
So try doing that.
그러니 그렇게 해보세요
Put in 1 or 2 more examples, because that will be then making use of Multi-shot prompting.
예제를 한두 개 더 넣으세요 MultiOut 프롬프트 사용이 될 테니까요
And you can add that to your resume that you've done multi-shot prompting.
멀티샷 프롬핑을 한 이력서에 추가할 수 있어요
I joke, of course, but but it is an important skill to have done and tried.
물론 농담이지만 시도해 본 중요한 기술이에요
But the reason it's useful is that when you do this, you improve the quality and reliability of the
하지만 이 방법이 유용한 이유는 LLM에 보내는 전화의 품질과 신뢰도를 높일 수 있기
call to the LLM.
때문이죠
Adding more uh, examples into the prompt strengthens the its, its ability to reliably predict the
예제를 추가하면 다음 토큰과 무엇을 예측할지 더욱 확실하게
next tokens and what you want it to be predicting.
알 수 있죠
So this is a good exercise to do.
좋은 운동이 되겠어요
It's a good way to add more robustness to this LLM call.
이 LLM 호출에 더 견고한 걸 추가하는 좋은 방법이죠
And it's something that we'll be doing along the course.
코스를 따라 계속 진행할 거예요
And it's something that you'll want to incorporate in your own projects.
여러분의 프로젝트에 포함하고 싶은 것이죠
So please do give that a try and say give that a shot, give that a multi shot.
그러니 그걸 시도해 보세요 그걸 시도해 보세요, 멀티샷이요
So and I also I mentioned that towards the end of the course we're going to be using this technique
제가 말씀드린 것처럼 과정 막바지에는 구조화 출력이라는 기술을
called structured outputs.
사용할 텐데요
That actually forces the LLM to respond in a particular way.
LLM이 특정한 방식으로 반응하도록 강요하는 거죠
But still Multi-shot prompting helps giving it that extra context that that extra sort of flavor for
그래도 멀티샷 홍보가 도움이 돼요 여러분이 원하는 것에 대해 추가적인 컨텍스트와 개성을
what you're looking for.
부여하죠
Um, and then just things you can do for the second call to generate the brochure.
두 번째 통화에서 할 수 있는 일은 책자를 생성하는 거예요
We already talked, of course, about using the system prompts to make it be snarky or sarcastic or
시스템 프롬프트에서 비꼬거나 빈정대는 것을 만드는 것에 대해 이미 얘기했었죠
whatever.
시스템 프롬프트를 이용해 다른 언어로 생성할 수 있다고 말씀드렸죠 스페인어
like Spanish.
같은 거요
There's another thing you could do there which might be more, certainly more interesting.
다른 방법도 있어요 훨씬 더 흥미로울 거예요
I don't know if it will get you a better result or not.
Get it로 더 좋은 결과가 나올지는 모르겠지만요
And that would be generate the brochure in English and then make a second call.
영어로 책자를 만들고 두 번째 전화를 걸었어요
Actually, of course, it's a third call to the LLM to translate the brochure from English to Spanish.
사실 LLM에 거는 세 번째 전화예요 책자를 영어로 스페인어로 번역하는 거죠
Uh, now, in many ways it's probably actually not going to be any better to do it that way in this
여러 면에서 이런 식으로 한다고 더 나을 건 없을 거예요
But by getting into that practice of doing that, you could imagine that we might use a model that is
하지만 그렇게 하는 연습에 들어가면 번역을 목적으로 특별히 훈련된 모델을
actually specially trained for the purposes of translation, and so you could use that model just for
사용할 수 있다고 상상할 수 있어요 그 모델을 그 목적만을 위해 사용할 수 있죠 그럼 더
that purpose, and that would then allow you for sure to get a better outcome using one model that's
나은 결과를 확실히 얻을 수 있도록 합니다 브로슈어 생성을 위해 훈련된
trained for brochure generation and a different model that's trained for translation.
모델 하나와 번역을 위해 훈련된 다른 모델을 이용해서요
And so whilst we will in fact probably be using just GPT four or mini for both purposes, it certainly
두 가지 목적으로 GPT 4, 또는 미니를 사용할 테지만
gives you that hands on experience of making the multiple calls.
다중 호출을 하는 경험을 확실히 제공하죠
And again, that's basically a miniature implementation of Agentic AI.
에이전트 인공지능의 미니어처 구현이죠
So again, great thing to get into the habit of doing, even if you could probably just use the system
습관을 들이기 좋은 방법이죠 시스템 프롬프트만 사용해도 1배시 안에
prompt to do it all in 1 in 1 bash.
모두 할 수 있어요 get it
Anyway, those are the things to do.
어쨌든 그런 걸 해야 해요
This will really help build your your confidence and your experience with these kinds of techniques,
이런 기술을 익힌 경험과 자신감을 쌓는 데 도움이 될 거예요 앞으로 몇
which will come in extremely useful in the upcoming weeks.
주간 아주 유용하게 쓰일 거예요
And then I have an exercise for you, and this is where you'll be building something from scratch.
그런 다음 실습을 할 거예요 처음부터 뭔가를 만드는 거죠
And to show you that, I will take you to the next video back to JupyterLab.
그걸 보여드리기 위해 주피터랩의 다음 비디오를 보여드리죠